Matthew Gilliland

Full Stack Web Developer

Detail-oriented Full Stack Web Developer specializing in the MERN stack. Fast learner with the ability to deliver quality work in a stressful and time-crunched environment. Lead developer of the first official mobile app for uAlbany. Looking forward to bringing a strong work ethic, eagerness to learn new technologies and frameworks, and the ability to solve problems on the fly.

New York, NY mgilliland23@gmail.com (845) 532-6154

LinkedIn: http://bit.ly/2KcZmMP
Github: http://bit.ly/2Kbwy7e
Portfolio: http://bit.ly/311KilB

LANGUAGES, FRAMEWORKS, AND TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML5, CSS3, Javascript
- MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js)
- Angular 2
- Heroku
- SQL

- AWS Amplify, S3,
- Visual Studio Code
- Git and Github
- C++
- Java

EXPERIENCE

Cherry Hill Construction, Accord, NY — Owner

July 2015 - PRESENT

- Co-owner and operator of successful residential construction and contracting company specializing in new home construction.
- Maintained acute attention to details while working on tight budgets and/or timelines.
- Created and sustained strong relationships with many clients and General contractors in the area.

North Fork Web, Long Island, NY — Web & Mobile *Application Developer*

July 2014 - July 2015

- Took new app ideas from concept to development
- Researched the best way to execute an app idea, and then developed it
- Managed a remote web development team.

University At Albany, Albany, NY — *Lead Developer*

January 2014 - May 2014

- Designed and developed the first official uAlbany Mobile app for Android and iOS
- Worked with many different departments within the university to link their resources and present them in a consistent UI.
- Launched the app in just six months.

EDUCATION

Columbia University, New York, NY — Certificate – Full Stack Web Developer

April 2019 - September 2019

University At Albany, Albany, NY — M.S. Computer Science - Magna Cum Laude

August 2014 - December 2014

University At Albany, Albany, NY — B.S. Computer Science & Applied Mathematics, minor in Business January 2011 - June 2014

PROJECTS

UAlbany Mobile App, University at Albany, Lead Developer

January 2014 - May 2014

The idea was to bring a number of pre-existing resources into a single, easy to navigate UI. ** Please note, I was involved with the development of Version 1.0. Version 2.0 seems to have many bugs according to reviews and is a very different UI/UX than what I developed.**

- Front End: HTML, CSS, Javascript | Back End: Parsing RSS, JSON, and XML feeds from back end
- Phonegap/Cordova to deploy to native mobile apps
- Released on Apple App Store and Google Play Store within 6 months of beginning development
- https://apps.apple.com/us/app/ualbany/id886698984
- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=edu.mobileapp.UAlbany&hl=en_US